# Rivaldi Rizalul Akhsan

**Backend Developer** 

082231709203 rivaldyrizalul@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/rivaldyrizal/ Jember, East Java

#### SUMMARY

Experienced in Software Engineering with more than 2 years of experience in Software Development. Enthusiastic in Programming and eager to contribute to reaching the company goals through hard work and keep learning new things. That's the reason I am a specialist in Backend Software Development.

Really happy to write clean, maintainable, and readable code.

#### EXPERIENCE

**Backend Developer** 02/2022 - 02/2023

Kampus Merdeka

- Responsible for developing, maintaining, and improving server and database systems that support applications or websites.
- Involved in API development projects and worked closely with the frontend development team and other technical teams within the company.
- Developed databases and server configurations for new websites.
- · Fixed bugs and issues in existing systems.
- Wrote technical documentation and explained the system to developers and other team members.

Skills: Go (Programming Language) · Git · REST APIs · PostgreSQL · CI/CD · Redis · Docker · GCP

## Ruangguru CAMP 2022 Graduate

02/2022 - 07/2022

Ruangguru

Completing Backend Engineering Bootcamp by Ruangguru

Skills: Go (Programming Language) · JavaScript · Git · REST APIs · SQLite · Unit Testing · Design Patterns

**Software Engineer** 11/2021 - 02/2022

GovTech Edu

GovTech Edu is an organization that was formed in 2020 and worked directly with the government and the Ministry of Education, Culture, Research and Technology, as well as part of Telkom Indonesia.

- · Developed front-end and back-end of the website
- · Designing new features for the website
- Maintain the website & bug fixing

Skills: JavaScript · Git · PostgreSQL · PHP

**Web Developer** 08/ - 01/2021

**UM Green Campus** 

- Manage and develop the website to improve the organization target to reach more than 100+ visitors per day
- Collaborate with other divisions such as graphic design and content writer to improve, build, and maintain the website
- Success to improved State University of Malang position from rank 57 in 2019 to rank 26 in 2020 in the UI GreenMetric World University Rankings

Skills: WordPress

## **Database Programming Teaching Assistant**

03/2019 - 06/2019

Universitas Negeri Malang

Assisting bachelor students and giving class tutorials about Database courses using DBMS platform, like Database object, SQL, Relations and Join, Stored Procedure, etc.

Skills: SQL Database · MySQL

## **Data Structure and Algorithm Teaching Assistant**

03/2019 - 06/2019

Universitas Negeri Malang

Assisting bachelor student and giving class tutorial about Algorithm and Data Structures

including queue, stack, etc

Skills: Algorithms · Data Structures · C++

Web Developer 02/2019 - 05/2019

Depeatement Teknik Elektro UM

- As a programmer (Back end specialist) Build and maintain the website using PHP and JS programing language with several frameworks (Codelgniter, Bootstrap)
- Build and develop a website for the electrical engineering department of the State University of Malang to help improve services
- · Collaborate with other development teams to integrate with other systems to improve the website
- · Currently, the website has been used by more than 1000+ users

Skills: Bootstrap · MySQL · Codelgniter · PHP

## **Assistant of Basic Programming Lecturer**

09/2018 - 12/2018

Universitas Negeri Malang

Assistant of Mr. Dr. Wahyu Sakti Gunawan Irianto, M.Kom. Assisting bachelor student and giving class tutorials about operator, conditions, and making projects with c++ language

Skills: C++

# EDUCATION

Informatic Education 2021

Universitas Negeri Malang - Bachelor of Education

## CERTIFICATES

**Golang Course Completion Certificate | Progate** 

08/2022 - Present

Backend Engineering Bootcamp Certificate | Ruangguru

07/2022 - Present

## SKILLS

Go (Programing Language)

REST API

CI/CD

Laravel

PostgreSQL

PHP

JavaScript SQL Database Docker WordPress

English Indonesian